scotreferendum.com 2015-11-12

# Scotland's Referendum 2014 | Privacy Policy

The Scottish Government seeks to ensure that the information published on this website is up to date and accurate. However, the information on the website does not constitute legal or professional advice and the Scottish Government cannot accept any liability for actions arising from its use. The Scottish Government cannot be held responsible for the contents of any pages referenced by an external link.

Any personal data collected through this website will be treated as confidential in line with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998.

**Twitter Policy**

The Scottish Government referendum Twitter account @scotreferendum is managed by the Digital Communications team.  
Tweets will be about: Scottish Government referendum news.  
Following: We will not automatically follow anyone who follows us. Being followed by @scotreferendum does not imply an endorsement of any kind.  
Availability: Social media channels will usually be updated during office hours Monday to Friday 9am to 5pm.  
Twitter may occasionally be unavailable, we accept no responsibility for interruptions in service due to Twitter downtime.  
@Replies and Direct Messages: We will respond to @ replies where it is appropriate to do so. The Scottish Government cannot engage on issues of party politics.

**Blog**

All comments submitted are moderated in advance of being made public. There may be a time delay between submission and posting. Anything that is abusive, indecent, unlawful or defamatory will not be displayed. Individuals are personally liable for the comments they submit. E-mail addresses will not be displayed.

**Information Collection**

The Scottish Government is the sole owner of the information collected on [scotreferendum.com](http://referendum.scot/). The Scottish Government processes personal data for the purposes of aiding its work with the Scottish Ministers to improve the well-being of Scotland and its people.

**Registration**

A user does not have to register to use the Scottish Government website, but a user must register if they wish to receive daily, weekly or monthly news, information and updates about the Government via email.

The registration information we require to allow a user to register is the full name and email address of the user if they wish to receive email updates.

**Sharing**

Legal Disclaimer  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

Third Party Intermediaries  
We use an outside contractor to manage our user database. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

Service Providers  
We partner with other third parties to provide specific services. For example database development, push mobile technology and hosting. When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information including mobile number and full contact information with the third party service providers so that the third party can supply these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**Links**

This Website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, the Scottish Government, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website.
